# SAM KNOPIK

sknopik@pembrokehill.org samknopik48@gmail.com

## American Football Coaches Association

Board of Trustees (2013-'17) International Series Coordinator (2022-Present)

# Missouri Football Coaches Association

President (2011-'13) Martel Service Award (2016) Hall of Fame Inductee (2024)

# **Greater KC Football Coaches Association**

President (2016-'18) Man of the Year (2013) Hall of Fame Inductee (2024)

# **Kansas City Chiefs**

Coach of the Year (2011) Coach of the Week ('03, '11, '12, '18, '19, '22, '24)

#### Lyric Opera of Kansas City

Community Advisory Council (2023-Present)

#### Brown v. Board Foundation

Board of Directors (2017-'21)

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

**State of Missouri** Social Studies (7-12) Physical Education (K-12)

## **REFERENCES**

Mr. David Burke, Assistant Principal, Pembroke Hill School dburke@pembrokehill.org

**Mr. Mike Hill**, Principal, Pembroke Hill School mhill@pembrokehill.org

#### **SUMMARY**

I desire to utilize my diverse background experiences in education to serve an international school by providing unique flexibility in skills to be used as needed by school administration. Over my 27-year teaching career I have taught 9th-12 grade students in courses including Ancient World History, Modern World History, American History, World Geography and College Dual-Credit World Geography. I hold active teaching certifications in both Social Studies and Physical Education. Administratively, I have served in roles such as athletic administration, director of community service and leadership. I have the vision, relationship skills, and experience to help lead a division, a department, a classroom, and a team.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Administration/Teacher/Coach, Pembroke Hill School

Kansas City, Missouri— 2003-Present My career at Pembroke Hill School, a private PreK-12 college preparatory institution has allowed me to serve in several roles.

- World History Instructor (2003-Present)
  - Sponsored Academic World Quest team (2023-Present)
  - Sponsored National History Day (2003-Present)
  - Silent Heroes Normandy Institute Participant (2017)
  - Sponsored Championship NHD Project (2010)
- Assistant Athletic Director (2013-2023)
- Community Service Director (2005-2015)
  - o Led service trips to Guatemala (2x's), Vietnam
- PE Instructor (2003-2013)
- Head Football Coach (2003-Present)
- Global Online Academy Online Teaching Participant (2013)

#### Classroom Teacher, Kyiv International School

Kyiv, Ukraine— 1998-1999

- Coached basketball and track teams
  - Led team trips to Prague & Cairo

# Classroom Teacher, Truman High School

Independence, Missouri—2001-2003

World Geography

#### **Classroom Teacher, Moberly High School**

Moberly, Missouri-1999-2001

World Geography Dual-Credit

#### **EDUCATION**

#### University of Missouri - Columbia

M.Ed.— 1998

Member of the University of Missouri Teaching Fellowship Program.

#### William Jewell College

BA.History — 1996